Omaha Powwow Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: 1984 Omaha Tribal Powwow
  - Subseries 1: Photographs
    - Sub-subseries 2: Color photographs
      - Camera roll, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-7; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Evening (Box 5)
        1-3 Gourd Dances
        4-20 Grand Entry
      - Camera roll, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-8; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Evening (Box 5)
        1-2 Intertribal
        3 Junior Girls' Shawl Dance
        4-5 Whipman's Special
        6-18 Eagle Feather Presentation with Hethu'shka Society
        19-20 Child naming
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-9; 18 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Afternoon (Box 5)
        1-4 Clyde Hallowell Special
        5-6 Tail Dancers Special
        7-16 Grand Entry
        17-18 Intertribal
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-10; 18 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Afternoon (Box 5)
        1-7 Eagle Feather Presentation and Special
        8 Water Carrier
        10-18 Junior Girls Shawl Dancers
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-11; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Afternoon (Box 5)
        1 Junior Girls Traditional
        2-7 Little Boys' Traditional
        8-10 Junior Girls Traditional
        11-12 Junior Boys Fancy Dancers
        13-14 Intertribal
        15-17 Junior Boys Traditional
        18-20 Junior Girls Shawl
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-12; 18 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Afternoon (Box 6)
        1-4 Junior Girls Shawl
        5 Fancy Dance Exhibition
        6-13 Sneak-up
        14-19 Flag-lowering ceremony and Special
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-13; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Late afternoon; early evening (Box 6)
        1 Ponca family
        2-4 Dennis Hastings, James and Charles Edwards
        5-20 Grand Entry
      - Camera roll, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-14; 15 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format); Evening (Box 6)
        3-4 Intertribal
        5-8 Drum Presentation and Dance to Clyde Hallowell
        9 Tiny Tots
        10 Women's Traditional
        11-12 Kenny Blackbird - flute
        13-14 Pow-wow Princess Special
        15 Joseph Harlan Special
      - Camera roll, August 13, 1984, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O84-DSL-15; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 6)
        1 Winnebago Historical Marker
        2-6 Hole in the Rock
        7-10 River site
        11-12 Mitchell family and Dennis Hastings
        13 Blackbird Bend
        14 Omaha Historical Marker
        15-20 Monument at Sioux City
  - Subseries 2: Sound recordings
    Archivist's note: Lee's original documentation has been used to describe the content, with minor edits for clarity. See Box-Folders 1/21 and 1/22.
    - Audio logs, 1984, 41 pages (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Tape 1, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR31; RYO 9900; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:40, Side 2: 00:31:55): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 2, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR32; RYP 4412; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:51, Side 2: 00:31:44): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 3, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR33; RYP 4413; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:52, Side 2: 00:29:20): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 4, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR34; RYP 4414; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:13, Side 2: 00:29:52): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 5, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR35; RYP 4415; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:32:05, Side 2: 00:31:12): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 6, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR36; RYP 4416; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:36, Side 2: 00:30:29): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 7, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR37; RYP 4417; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:31, Side 2: 00:30:28): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 8, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR38; RYP 4418; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:31:26, Side 2: 00:31:39): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 9, August 11, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR39; RYP 4419; 1 sound cassette (00:15:52): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 10, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR40; RYP 4420; 1 sound cassette (00:30:17, 00:30:53): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 11, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR41; RYP 4421; 1 sound cassette (00:31:45, 00:31:11): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 12, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR42; RYP 4422; 1 sound cassette (00:31:37, 00:30:05): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 13, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR43; RYP 4423; 1 sound cassette (00:29:23, 00:29:39): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 14, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR44; RYP 4424; 1 sound cassette (00:31:38, 00:31:23): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 15, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR45; RYP 4425; 1 sound cassette (00:5:59, 00:31:38): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 16, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR46; RYP 4426; 1 sound cassette (00:24:18, 00:30:59): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 17, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR47; RYP 4427; 1 sound cassette (00:30:42, 00:31:38): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 18, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR48; RYP 4428; 1 sound cassette (00:30:18, 00:29:03): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 19, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR49; RYP 4429; 1 sound cassette (00:29:59, 00:31:34): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 20, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR50; RYP 4430; 1 sound cassette (00:30:16, 00:30:58): analog, 1 7/8 ips
    - Tape 21, August 12, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR51; RYP 4431; 1 sound cassette (00:27:04): analog, 1 7/8 ips
- Series 4: 1985 Omaha Tribal Powwow
  - Subseries 1: John Carter
    - Camera roll, September 1, 1985, AFC 1986/038: 255083-1; 36 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm; Afternoon (Box 2)
      1-6 Alan Jabbour, flanked by Hollis Stabler and an unidentified traditional dancer, dancing during the FCP honoring song
      7 Dennis Hastings and others during honoring dance
      8 Dorothy Sara Lee, Mrs. Stabler, Robbie Lonewolf, and others during honoring dance
      9 Erika Brady during honoring dance
      10-11 Honoring dance
      12-19 Presentation of plaque, blanket, and shawl to Alan Jabbour, Dorothy Lee, and Erika Brady
      20 Thanking the Host Drum for the song
      21-24 Presentations of Omaha LP
      25-28 Intertribal
      29-32 Camp shots
      33 Flag lowering
      34-35 Honoring song for flag
    - Black-and-white contact sheet and photo log, 1985, 1 photograph: contact sheet, black-and-white; approx. 8 1/2 in. x 11 in.; 4 pages (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Subseries 2: Dorothy Sara Lee
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: 233189-1; 37 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm (Box 2)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: 233189-2; 36 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm (Box 2)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: 233189-3; 35 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm (Box 2)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: 233189-4; 35 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm (Box 2)
    - Black-and-white contact sheets, 1985, 4 photographs: contact sheets, black and white; approx. 8 1/2 in. x 11 in. (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Black-and-white photo prints, 1985, 11 photographs: prints, black and white; 8 in. x 10 in. (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Subseries 3: Unidentified photographer
    The first box has the preferred version of images, and the second box has similar versions of those images.
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-1; 36 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 6)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-2; 38 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-3; 11 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-4; 34 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-5; 38 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-6; 36 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-7; 37 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-8; 32 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 7)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-9; 30 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 8)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-10; 25 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 8)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-11; 35 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 8)
    - Camera roll, 1985, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O85-12; 6 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Boxes 3, 8)
- Series 5: 1986 Omaha Tribal Powwow
  - Field notes, 1986, 8 pages (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Subseries 1: Black-and-white photographs
    - Black-and-white photo logs, 1986, 4 pages (Box-folder 1/27)
    - Camera roll, August 24, 1986, AFC 1986/038: 255083-2; 35 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm; Afternoon (Box 2)
      1-6 Contest judging: Little Boy's Traditional
      7-14 Intertribal
      15 Contest judging: Women's traditional
      16-17 Contest judging: Women's buckskin
      18-22 Contest judging: Men's Fancy
      23-31 Contest judging: Men's Traditional
      32-35 Tipis
    - Camera roll, August 24, 1986, AFC 1986/038: 255172-1; 36 photographs: film, negatives, black and white; 35 mm; Afternoon (Box 2)
      1-2 New drum shed
      3-4 Speaker's stand, new sign
      5-6 Drum shed
      7 Eagle feather presentation
      8-16 Grand Entry
      17-19 Flag song
      20-23 Intertribal
      24-25 Obermeyer gourd presentation to Dennis
      26-29, 31 Contest judging: Junior Boy's Trad.
      30 Contest table
      32-34 Contest judging: Jr. Boy's Fancy
      35-36 Junior Girl's Shawl
    - Black-and-white contact sheets, 1986, 2 photographs: contact sheets, black and white; approx. 8 1/2 in. x 11 in. (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Subseries 2: Color photographs
    - Camera roll, undated, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O86-DSL-1; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 4)
    - Camera roll, undated, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O86-DSL-2; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 4)
    - Camera roll, undated, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O86-DSL-3; 9 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 4)
    - Camera roll, undated, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O86-DSL-4; 20 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 4)
    - Camera roll, undated, AFC 1986/038: FCP/O86-DSL-5; 4 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm (slide format) (Box 5)
- Series 6: Interviews conducted by Alan Jabbour
  - John Turner, February 24, 1983, AFC 1986/038: SR84; RYS 3701; 1 sound cassette: analog, 1 7/8 ips
    Recorded in the Omaha Tribal Administration building, Macy, Nebraska. Recorded by Alan Jabbour, assisted by Dennis Hastings (others also present).
  - Dennis Hastings interview, October 24, 1984, AFC 1986/038: SR86; RYS 3703; 1 sound cassette: analog, 1 7/8 ips
  - Dennis Hastings interview: log and transcript, October 24, 1984 (Box-folder 1/29)
- Series 7: Unidentified sound recordings
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR52; RAA 59385; 1 sound tape reel (00:58:56, 00:09:02): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR53; RAA 59386; 1 sound tape reel (01:07:58): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR54; RAA 59387; 1 sound tape reel (01:07:58): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR55; RAA 59388; 1 sound tape reel (00:57:57, 00:10:11): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR56; RAA 59389; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:03, 00:13:10): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR57; RAA 59390; 1 sound tape reel (00:50:49, 00:17:21): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR58; RAA 59391; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:11, 00:13:14): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR59; RAA 59392; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:27, 00:12:41): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR60; RAA 59393; 1 sound tape reel (00:56:26, 00:11:57): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR61; RAA 59394; 1 sound tape reel (00:57:28, 00:10:52): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR62; RAA 59395; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:51, 00:12:24): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR63; RAA 59396; 1 sound tape reel (00:48:58, 00:22:36): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR64; RAA 59397; 1 sound tape reel (00:56:07, 00:15:26): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR65; RAA 59398; 1 sound tape reel (00:50:57, 00:20:30): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR66; RAA 59399; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:36, 00:15:39): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR67; RAA 59400; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:30, 00:12:43): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR68; RAA 59401; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:27, 00:13:02): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR69; RAA 59402; 1 sound tape reel (00:53:02, 00:15:01): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR70; RAA 59403; 1 sound tape reel (00:56:57, 00:11:07): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR71; RAA 59404; 1 sound tape reel (00:50:24, 00:17:46): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR72; RAA 59405; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:45, 00:12:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR73; RAA 59406; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:00, 00:13:19): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR74; RAA 59407; 1 sound tape reel (00:55:15): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR75; RAA 59408; 1 sound tape reel (00:58:29, 00:09:29): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR76; RAA 59409; 1 sound tape reel (00:52:31, 00:15:33): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR77; RAA 59410; 1 sound tape reel (00:54:53, 00:13:05): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR78; RAA 59411; 1 sound tape reel (00:53:48, 00:14:01): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR79; RAA 59412; 1 sound tape reel (00:52:19, 00:15:42): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR80; RAA 59413; 1 sound tape reel (00:54:48, 00:13:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR81; RAA 59414; 1 sound tape reel (00:50:54, 00:17:22): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR82; RAA 59415; 1 sound tape reel (00:56:44, 00:11:27): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 1986/038: SR83; RAA 59416; 1 sound tape reel (00:59:52): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track; 10 in.